<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[AdProof Marketing Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-09T12:38:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.adproof.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[AdProof]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write Better Headlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/write-better-headlines/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T02:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/write-better-headlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Writing effective headlines are a great way to make your article stand out. Remember that a headline is just one word or phrase that summarizes an article or the key point of your content. It is meant to clarify to the audience, what you are going to talk about. It is an effective communication tool to grab the readers&#8217; attentions. Once the reader has been reeled in, it is your article’s job to keep the readers engaged.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Research Popular Headlines</h2>

<p>Would not it be a waste for a captivating article to be left unread? First things first: you need to understand your target audience. A great headline to you might not be as eye-catching to them.  To help you understand them, study headlines of other articles or the aforementioned template headings that have proven to exert a pull on the readers. Do not copy them, but instead dissect them and learn how they were structured to become skilled at creating your own catchy headings. Next, choose the right words and phrases; keep your readers at bay because a dull and boring caption will not even make them give your article a second glance.</p>

<p>Use an intriguing rhetorical question as your headline.  If your question is worded carefully it’ll be easy to hold the audience. You can simply make a strong statement that clearly demonstrates that what the content will further define in your article.</p>

<h2>5 Headline Tips</h2>

<p>Attention is crafted via a good header. So, what are some good tips to develop an interesting headline for a great article?</p>

<ol>
<li>Starting off with “Who Wouldn&#8217;t Want&#8230;&#8221; is a classic when the article is about a product or about something that needs to happen, because people will always desire something that someone else has and they do not.</li>
<li>Another phrase that can be used is &#8220;The Secret of&#8230;&#8221;. This is a powerful attention-grabber, as readers will instantly want to get in on this &#8216;secret&#8217; that your article is about.</li>
<li>People will always appreciate something content that would literally help them, therefore a phrase like &#8220;A Method That’s Helping (specific class or group of people) to (specific action or task that they find difficult) will definitely do the magic trick.</li>
<li>Using &#8220;Little Known Ways to (specific action or task)&#8221; is also one of the effectual ways of constructing a title. This is a more intriguing, uncommon version of “The Secret of&#8230;”.</li>
<li>A popular phrase used by articles that promote a certain product or action or even lifestyle is &#8220;Get Rid of (a specific problem that readers face) Once and For All&#8221;. Take a common problem that your readers face, and tell them that your article can help them overcome it.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Example Headlines</h2>

<ol>
<li>&#8220;Quick and Easy Ways to solve (a specific problem)&#8221; also works since people, you and even I love easy solutions to problems.</li>
<li>&#8220;Now You Can Also Have&#8221; is a very attractive header, because majority of us will always desire more things.</li>
<li>&#8220;Be Like a Celebrity&#8221; is great for articles about beauty/health/fitness.</li>
<li>&#8220;Have or Build Something You Can Be Proud Of!&#8221; appeals to vanity and dissatisfaction.</li>
<li>&#8220;What Everybody Needs To Know about (a specific topic)&#8221; not only attracts people into reading the body of your article, but also challenges them to read the article and test their knowledge on the topic.</li>
</ol>


<h2>KISS Headlines</h2>

<p>Keep it simple stupid (KISS). There are plenty of ways to write an effective headline. But there are certain types of them that have proven to literally attract millions of viewers. The essence of aforementioned information is based on the following simple steps:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn from previous headlines.</li>
<li>Understand your audience.</li>
<li>Test by using headline formulas.</li>
<li>Push it live.</li>
<li>That&#8217;s it!</li>
</ul>


<p>Now you are capable of working out your own headlines.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get 237 Beta Testers For Your Awesome Startup Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/startups/get-237-beta-testers-for-your-awesome-startup-now/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T02:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/startups/get-237-beta-testers-for-your-awesome-startup-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I entered search mode to find resources to spotlight <a href="http://adproof.com" title="AdProof: A/B Testing for Google Adwords, Bing Ads and Facebook Ads">AdProof</a> and get beta testers. The results were <a href="http://www.udemy.com/blog/beta-testers/">good</a>, <a href="http://www.betabait.com">bad</a> and <a href="http://www.betausersnow.com">ugly</a>.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Top Three Places to Submit Startup</h2>

<p>The 3 places, in order of importance, you need to submit your startup to now:</p>

<ol>
<li><a href="http://betali.st" title="Beta List">Beta List</a></li>
<li><a href="http://startupli.st" title="Startup List">Startup List</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.startupplays.com/" title="Startup Plays">Startup Plays</a></li>
</ol>


<h2>Winner #1: Beta List</h2>

<p><a href="http://betali.st/startups/adproof" title="Beta List">Beta List</a> was the first site that showed up for the search:</p>

<p><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=beta+users+startup&amp;oq=beta+users+startup&amp;aqs=chrome.0.57j62l2.8237&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">beta users startup</a></p>

<p>I signed up using my <a href="https://twitter.com/adproof" title="AdProof on Twitter">AdProof Twitter account</a> and was off to the races. I started reading through the instructions and noticed this text:</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Please note at this time we only accept startups that are not yet publicly accessible. Feel free to submit anyway so we have your info on file for the future. Full details here.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>Crap!!! I need beta users, like yesterday, and this is not helping. I dragged along and then stumbled on a free pass for $15. The pass guarantees publication within 48 hours (only took me a few hours). Here&#8217;s the short story. It cost me $15, yielded 200 beta users, and took less than 24 hours. W00T!</p>

<p><strong>Results:</strong> Currently about 200 sign ups.</p>

<h2>Protip #1</h2>

<p>In all my startup experience I&#8217;ve found it extremely vital to achieve small wins every day. If you&#8217;re not winning, you&#8217;re losing and that&#8217;s not healthy for the psyche. This was my small win that day.</p>

<h2>Winner #2: Startup Plays</h2>

<p>I stumbled on this precious gem after, <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a>, from the awesome <a href="http://www.startupplays.com/" title="Startup Plays">Startup Plays</a>, signed up for the private beta via <a href="http://betali.st/startups/adproof" title="Beta List">Beta List</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a> emailed me and asked if I&#8217;d like to be featured on his monthly blog post called, <a href="www.startupplays.com/blog/top-35-startups-in-tech-that-techcrunch-missed-out-on-january-2013/" title="Top 35 Startups In Tech that TechCrunch missed out on January 2013">Top 35 Startups In Tech that TechCrunch missed out on January 2013</a>. There&#8217;s no way I&#8217;d pass up on that, so I emailed <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a> back with a short description of <a href="http://adproof.com" title="AdProof: Create High Performing Ads for Google, Bing and Facebook">AdProof</a> and screenshot.</p>

<p>What did I learn here? Reach out to awesome startup bloggers, like <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a>, on Twitter or email and make it super personal. If they email you first then be sure to respond back within 10 minutes. The goal here is stay fresh in their mind while keeping it super personal.</p>

<p><strong>Results:</strong> Currently about 30 sign ups.</p>

<h2>Protip #2</h2>

<p>Protip: If you&#8217;re not monitoring your brand terms with <a href="http://www.google.com/alerts" title="Google Alerts">Google Alerts</a> and <a href="https://ifttt.com" title="If This, Then That">IFTTT</a> (If This, Then That) then do that now. I&#8217;m currently monitoring my brand terms with Google Alerts using this query:</p>

<ul>
<li>-site:adproof.com &#8220;adproof&#8221;</li>
<li>-site:adproof.com adproof</li>
</ul>


<p>Ive setup a recipe for each Google Alert, using the RSS feed, inside IFTTT to SMS me. Here&#8217;s my recipe if you need: <a href="https://ifttt.com/myrecipes/personal/2774260/share" title="AdProof IFTTT">AdProof IFTTT Google Alert Recipe</a>. Remember to update the title and change the URL to your own Google Alert RSS URL.</p>

<h2>Winner #3: Startup List</h2>

<p>I gotta say, <a href="http://startupli.st/" title="Startup List">Startup List</a> has got their crap together. Not only can you submit your <a href="http://startupli.st/adproof" title="AdProof on Startup List">awesome startup</a>, you can also manage it inside a pretty dashboard. This is a great idea because startups change, ummm, frequently. So if your startup updates the homepage, or you want to tidy up your description, or add a video or even a new social media username, then you can do that here. My initial submission didn&#8217;t get the response necessary to make the homepage, but a quick email to the helpful <a href="thenickfrost" title="Nick Frost from Startup List">@thenickfrost</a> fixed all that. Friendly group of guys over there.  High recommend.</p>

<p><strong>Results:</strong> Currently about 20 sign ups.</p>

<h2>The Bad and Ugly</h2>

<p>I stumbled on a few other sites to submit your startup, but they&#8217;re all stuck in &#8216;pending&#8217;. I think these sites have potential, but are super duper slow in their moderation process.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="inspiredbeta.com" title="Inspired Beta">Inspired Beta</a> - Stuck in &#8216;Your membership account has not been activated yet&#8217; hell.</li>
<li><a href="momb.socio-kybernetics.net" title="Museum of Modern Betas">MoMB or The Museum of Modern Betas</a> - This site appeared to be active during the time, but now I&#8217;m not thinking so much. I sent an email to the author, via the footer, but didn&#8217;t get a response.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Don&#8217;t Miss Next Post</h2>

<p>Stay tuned. You won&#8217;t want to miss the next blog post. I&#8217;m going to show you what worked and what didn&#8217;t when I applied advertising tactics to get beta users. I&#8217;ll show you what worked and what failed miserably. I&#8217;ll show you how I sent over <a href="http://adproof.com" title="Facebook Ads tactic that yielded 250 users in less than 5 minutes">250 users from Facebook Ads in less than 5 minutes</a> for $10. Yes, I used <a href="http://adproof.com" title="AdProof: A/B Testing for Google Adwords, Bing Ads and Facebook Ads">AdProof</a>. Which reminds me… are you <a href="http://adproof.com" title="Sign up for AdProof private beta">signed up for our private beta</a>, yet? We&#8217;re closing the private beta once we reach 1,000.</p>

<h2>Sharing is Caring Blah, Blah, Blah</h2>

<p>If you enjoyed this post then share it or else… just kidding. No, seriously, please share the post. Thanks ;-)</p>

<h2>Need Help?</h2>

<p>I learned a ton about getting beta users with this exercise. So if you need any tips, please shoot a tweet to <a href="http://twitter.com/jonathannelson" title="Message on @jonathannelson on Twitter">@jonathannelson</a> and I promise to respond.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ad Copy Demystified]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/ad-copy-demystified/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T01:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/ad-copy-demystified</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What’s an advertisement? An advertisement is any notice or announcement to promote an idea, product, service or an event. It could be announced through the television, radio, or the internet. There are endless possibilities when it comes to how you want to advertise your item or idea. Some people go through vigorous pains and have huge events to officially announce their items while others do it more quietly on television or internet. Not only do advertisements help customers getting familiarized with the product but also help the company that is promoting it. Something more efficient than an advertisement is an advertising copy; or Ad copy for short. But what is an advertising copy?</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>What Exactly Is Ad Copy?</h2>

<p>Advertising copy can be found anywhere on the internet. In the search results. In your Facebook or Twitter feed. They are created specifically to catch someone’s eyes, and eventually make said person click the ad copy. Usually Ad copies are either contextual or pay per click. Ad copies can be actually anything; from catchy product titles to enticing product pictures with text on them. Text of the ad copy is usually the second or third line of an ad displayed on a search engine result page or any other web page. Most ad copy makers usually add keywords about usage of the product along with the few catchy lines. This is to gather more audience for their ads. When a person searches a specific keyword on a search engine they will be linked to the ad copy if it has anything to do with it.</p>

<h2>Ad Copy – A Bridge Between Search Results and Websites</h2>

<p>Present time marketing is becoming more challenging to handle. With each passing day it is becoming more aggressive. Since there is always competition in the marketplace you need to make sure that your ad copies are distinct, unique and eye catching. It basically serves as the communication point between the search results and your website. The more you make your ad copies attractive the more appealing they will be towards everyday consumers. Make sure to include details about your product in your ad copy while you are at it, keep the FAQs of the general audience in mind. For example, how helpful it is compared to other products, advantages, disadvantages but more importantly, keep it short and simple. Because the last thing you would want is a dull ad that no one pays attention to.</p>

<h2>What’s the Goal of Your Ad?</h2>

<p>Focus on the goal you are creating an ad for. Interest a customer by informing them how your product can change their life, as clearly as possible. This is a vital ingredient for the ad copy. You need to include how far superior your item is towards others and how much more it can help your customers in changing their life. But do this indirectly as you do not want to stir trouble by openly bashing against a specific product or company. Your main goal should be to define the unique points of your product/service since they tend to attract customers into making a direct action. The probability rises if there is call to actions in your ads because the viewers are keen to mimic them.</p>

<p>Building credibility should be one of your advertisement goals. Offer the audience believability about the product, brand, or idea that you are advertising about. If your product is linked to everyday life it’ll have a better chance of being bought.</p>

<h2>Details, Details, Details</h2>

<p>Another core ingredient in your ad copy is grammar and punctuation. This is extremely important. You need to use simple words to get your idea crystal-clear to the audience. Do not pick lengthy words at random and put them in your ad copy thinking it’ll make it sound intelligent. It won’t. It also won’t help people understand what you’re talking about. Be specific and straight to the point. Remember you want your product to make an impression on people.</p>

<h2>Test-Drive your Ad</h2>

<p>At last before ever going out to make an ad copy or to even think about advertising your time you need to test your product, item, or idea. Will it attract everyday consumers? Does it spark an interest in someone? What things is it capable that other products are not. Ask yourself these questions before you advertise. More importantly do not promise consumers anything about your item. It is bad for your company image if you’re caught lying. Remember, make a good impression on people and they will definitely come back for more.</p>

<h2>Have You Signed Up for AdProof Yet?</h2>

<p>AdProof is the first test-driven advertising platform that lets ad buyers test before they spend. Ad buyers can now A/B test any ad group for just a $1. AdProof is super fast. No more wasted hours waiting for data or approval of ads. You’ll get results back in minutes. AdProof supports all ad types. Test your PPC ads, display ads, and social media ad campaigns. AdProof supports all devices. Optimize your ads for desktops &amp; laptops, mobile devices and tablets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
