<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The @AdProof Marketing Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-16T10:20:13-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.adproof.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[AdProof]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Secrets to Creating Great Offers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/marketing/secrets-to-creating-great-offers/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T08:53:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/marketing/secrets-to-creating-great-offers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Offers play quite a superior role in the whole subject of marketing. They are efficient tools used to gain leads and also to advance the already present leads in such a way that they attract more and more attention in sales. But not everyone understands what “offers” really mean and many get the idea confused with several other concepts. Using a marketing offer is vital for business so it is naturally even more vital for the term to be understood properly.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Why Should You Be Careful When Creating Marketing Offers?</h2>

<p>The term &#8220;offer&#8221; literally translates to granting something to someone so a marketing offer should also be granting something to the consumers; it shouldn’t ever be something of no use at all. Many offers are granted to the consumers after they fill a form of sorts, it is a common thing. But the point should always be remembered that whatever it is that you’re offering after they have filled forms should be useful and not disappointing because no one likes to waste time just to get something useless.</p>

<h2>4 Types of Great Offers That Can&#8217;t Fall Flat</h2>

<p>Generally, there are 4 basic types of offers that are actually effectual for a company to raise leads. While many offers to tend to bring out some at least a degree of response from the consumers, these 4 types of offers are the types that are sure to get a response from the consumers, maybe even a large one. This is why these 4 kinds of offer are so important for marketing. These 4 types are:</p>

<h3>Offers That Raise Response and Lower Risk</h3>

<p>Offers that have the potential to raise response are the ones that offer people something while promising them to not take anything in return. Along with that, offers that are limited, offering free things, and asking people’s advice are also the ones that are bound to raise response. To lower the risks of offers, you grant them something useful, reassure them in some way that they wouldn’t face any loss and at the same time make sure that they stay with you or try your wares. This works out for the consumer and the marketer both; the consumer believes to have no harm in taking a chance at your offer, and the marketer gets the advantage of a potential customer. Like in the Money-Back Guarantee, the consumers have the benefit of getting their money back if they are dissatisfied and the marketer has the advantage of getting people to actually give their product a try, so it works out for everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Examples of low-risk responsive offers:</strong> <em>Limited Time Offer, Free Gift, Free Trial, Money-Back Guarantee, Yes/No, Double Your Money-Back Guarantee, Limited Time Trial, Long Term Warranty, etc.</em></p>

<h3>Offers That Reduce Price and Increase Urgency</h3>

<p>This type of offer is especially useful when your business has many competitors. Prices are a major factor when it comes to marketing and selling, so reduced costs for the consumers are always attractive and it helps bring in potential customers.  Of course, just giving away sale prices and appealing offers is not enough for majority of the people, since everyone hesitates before buying at least once. This is where the point of Increasing Urgency comes in. If your offers are emitting some kind of detail that lets the people know that they might not get this chance again, the hesitation factor is lessened and people are more inclined to buy, because as they see it, if they let go of the chance, it’s gone forever. This increases the value of the sale to them and also makes them feel better about buying a thing that could have been lost to them had they not bought it.</p>

<p><strong>Examples of offers that convey urgency:</strong> <em>Dollars Off, Group Discount, Introductory Price, Refunds and Rebates, Last Chance, Enrollment Period, Limited Time Offer, Potential Price Increasing Announcement, etc.</em></p>

<h3>Offers That Improve Terms, Add Services and Make Bribes</h3>

<p>While good offers go a long way to help increase sales and customers, offering additional advantages and services for the consumers works even better. For example, altering the payment method of their online sales or offering them multiple methods to pay so that they can choose the one that fits them, would help your sales since the people would be at ease to consume your sales and have no problems in their purchasing which also increases the potential of future additional sales. Similarly, granting the consumers no shipping charges or quick delivery services would ensure that the consumers feel better about purchasing as they won’t have to go anywhere and would receive everything at home without having to pay for it in any way, or they would prefer to buy from your business rather than others since you are the ones offering them quick delivery while other businesses deliveries could take days. To foolproof your offer even more, try adding additional things for the customer so that the offer becomes irresistible. Offering an extra free gift or providing a “buy one get one free” offer helps a lot in sales as the offer becomes hard to let go of for the consumers.</p>

<p><strong>Examples of offers that improve terms, offer service and bribe:</strong> <em>Bill Me Later, Risk Free Offer, Free Shipping, Free Gift etc.</em></p>

<h3>Offers That Increase Profits and Generate Inquiries</h3>

<p>While you are focusing on getting good, solid responses from the consumers after your offer, your main aim is still to gain as much profit as possible, which can only be done via a good response from the customers. There are some tactics that can be used to make offers that are irresistible yet profitable to you, such as Deluxe Versions of things, in which you offer a product at normal price and offer another better version of the product along with it for a discounted price; this way you sell two products instead of one and the consumer gets a good deal. For products that can’t be sold in a single step, you need schemes to promote them and to raise their awareness. This includes offering up free information or free gift for inquiry with sales so that your product can gain inquiries. Some other such schemes include Free Demonstration, Sales Call, Free Subscription, Free Membership on One, Free Samples, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 3 Essentials for PPC Beginners]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/the-3-essentials-for-ppc-beginners/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T20:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/the-3-essentials-for-ppc-beginners</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>PPC or pay-per-click advertisements play a significant role in a company’s online marketing campaign. PPCs, when bought from reputable companies like Microsoft and Google, can also have a significant price tag attached to it, which is why it may be important to use these advertisements to their maximum potential.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The best way to do this would be to split advertisements into different variations. However, once that is done, there are some things we need to keep in mind.</p>

<h2>Things to Remember</h2>

<p>Firstly, we need to focus on giving the advertisement as much disclosure as possible. The best way to do this would be to integrate a consumer’s search query within the advertisement itself. This will highlight the advertisement in bold on the search page, giving the company an upper hand over others. Secondly, the advertisement will consist of the terms the consumer searched on, which will make it more appropriate for both sides.</p>

<p>Another thing that we have to keep in mind is our ability to compete.  Keeping an eye out for their messages would help us determine our stance in the market, as well as help us decide whether using aggressive marketing techniques or claims would be worth it. The best way to start of with this would be to determine how strong a company’s reputation is. A simple Google search may do the trick, and if the company uses other sources of media for advertisement like newspapers and TV, the PPCs could be made parallel to them, helping it reverberate within potential and existing customers.</p>

<h2>Significance of Keywords and Landing URLs</h2>

<p>Keywords and landing URL also play a significant role in where our advertisements end up. We can experiment by changing one keyword at a time, and comparing the results. For example, ‘buy’ can be substituted with ‘compare prices’, and the results could be gathered over time to show which words attract larger masses. As far as the landing URL goes, the company must make sure that clicking on the advertisement takes the customer to the product page and not the company&#8217;s homepage, unless the homepage doubles as a product page. Alternately, the company can also create a mini-website or a small portal for users who click on the advertisement, ensuring that customers find the information that they&#8217;re looking for.</p>

<h2>Clicks for Conversions and Conversions for the Bank</h2>

<p>When it comes to advertising successfully, it would be best to ignore the click-through rate (CTR) and focus more on the conversion rate. The conversion rate will help to determine how much money is being spent on every keyword, and how much returns they give, apart from telling us how often a click on the advertisement resulted in a meaningful action like a sale or sign-up. However factors like position and day of the week must be taken into account in order to reach an unbiased conclusion. Companies like Google may also offer services like Google Merchant Centre, which may give companies an extra platform for product extension.</p>

<p>Another important factor that may impact a company&#8217;s PPC would be its advertising budget. In some cases, the company may simply expect too much out of its advertising campaign at a very initial stage. This may result in the business giving up too soon, or it may simply run out of funds to continue its campaign before it turns profitable, although it may help if a company has a preplanned advertising budget.  A company must also learn to exploit the free tools offered by the advertising company to their maximum potential. For example, tools like Google Adwords can help calculate the conversion rate and cost per advertisement.</p>

<p>Getting started on PPC ads may be a significant step for a company, but the only way to maximize profits would be to use this opportunity in the most productive way possible. Thanks to the free tools being offered by most advertising companies, managing costs and productivity has gotten a lot easier. A perfect combination of patience and management would ultimately lead the company to success.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Become a Twitter Powerhouse]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/twitter/how-to-become-a-twitter-power-user/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T20:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/twitter/how-to-become-a-twitter-power-user</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every business needs one key element to stand out from the rest. This key element, in most cases, is advertisement. Gone are the days when advertising used to be limited to television, radios, magazines, and newspapers. In today’s time, most of the businesses spend a significant chuck of their advertisement budget on online advertising.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Importance of Online Advertising and Twitter’s Vital Role</h2>

<p>Online advertising helps a firm to get its message across the world in an extremely convenient manner. In addition to that, growing platforms like Facebook and Twitter have made it even easier to get your message across more than a 100 million users at surprisingly cheap rates. Twitter gives you the ability to send ‘tweets’, a short way of getting your message across in less than or equal to 160 characters.  This restriction is more of a blessing in disguise, since it helps you to keep your message short and sweet.</p>

<p>Anyone can sign up for Twitter and start using it right out of the box, whether it’s a business or an individual. However, one must keep in mind that Twitter is a game of ‘Hashtags’, which are small words that can help you highlight a topic. A good business or an individual would slowly work its way up and build a reputation, but that’s not something a GREAT business would do. A great business would learn to use such a versatile platform like Twitter in an extremely powerful or cost efficient manner. In other words, it would strive to become a power user.</p>

<h2>Why become a Twitter Power User?</h2>

<p>Being a power user would give the user substantial advantages. These include:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The number of people who follow you will increase at a steady rate. More followers mean a greater audience to get your message across. If you advertise your product’s website, the probability of users clicking on the link will grow higher by the day. This will lead to more clicks on the website and ultimately, increased web traffic.</p></li>
<li><p>If your tweet seems appealing to the followers, they may tweet or re-tweet your words, increasing your range to a much, much wider circle of audience.</p></li>
<li><p>Twitter is nothing short of a hashtag universe. Tweeting right and tweeting good will make your hashtag more prominent among the rest.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>These advantages are not achievable via any other source. Other social networks, such as Facebook, are not nearly as good as Twitter when it comes to spreading breaking news, blog posts or even self-promoting hyperbole. Each platform has its own charm, but if you play your cards right, you will have success welcoming you soon enough.</p>

<h2>The Characteristics of a Good Power User</h2>

<p>Now, the best way to begin tweeting as a power user would be to keep a few important factors in mind. These include:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The most important factor is that you should keep your tweets short, sweet and genuine. In cases like these, less is more.</p></li>
<li><p>You should consider re-tweeting your words, since there is a high chance that everyone may not have seen your post the first time.</p></li>
<li><p>Consider attending Tweetups. Tweetup consists of people with similar interest sitting together every month for a general meeting. This will not only make you more famous among your peers, but will also allow you to expand your knowledge at no additional cost. You get to kill two birds, no pun intended, with one stone!</p></li>
<li><p>You should spend some time in getting to know your audience. There’s practically no point in tweeting something which conflicts with your followers’ interests and likes. Knowing what your followers are interested in will make your job and your life much easier, as well as make your work far more efficient.</p></li>
<li><p>Stick to a tweeting schedule. I personally recommend <a href="http://twitter.com/bufferapp">@Buffer</a> for scheduling and posting tweets. Spend some time in figuring out the right time and the right way to get your message across. However, when you are in a conference or a similar kind of event, start tweeting like crazy! This is the one time you get to cross your limits. This is a great tactic for networking at conferences and events.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Becoming an ideal Twitter power user is not something that an individual can achieve within days, it consumes times. Patience is literally the key to success in this case. Those who play it slow and steady are sure to become the winners.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A/B Testing Google AdWords]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/a-b-testing-google-adwords/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-12T21:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/a-b-testing-google-adwords</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many online marketing campaigns regard pay-per-click (PPC) advertising as a vital component in its strategy. Apart from being amongst the most significant factors, it can also be the most expensive, which is why it&#8217;s vital to keep track of all the investments.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The first step towards leading an effective PPC campaign is to decide what to write in an advertisement. In order for the advertisement to work in our interest, there are four key factors we need to concentrate on. These consist of:</p>

<h2>The Headline</h2>

<p>The headline is the first line of the advertisement, and it must be strong enough to grasp the readers’ attention quickly. In this case, shorter is better. The headline is there to shine light upon what is being offered. An ideal length would be 4-5 words, but the aim here is to keep your message as short and to-the-point as possible. The headline will be in a different color than the rest of the text, usually blue. The headline may also consist of keywords that will show up in bold in a Google search.</p>

<h2>The Body Text</h2>

<p>The body text will consist of 1-2 lines, and should be similar to a page’s meta-tag description. Searchers will be looking for something that will give them a little more idea of what you have to offer, and your body text must be strong enough to convey the message.</p>

<h2>Keywords</h2>

<p>Take some time to think of what terms a consumer might search on to find your product or company. At this point, testing on what keywords work best and coming up with keyword-advertisement combinations will help you succeed.</p>

<h2>The Landing Page</h2>

<p>The landing page also pays an important part in PPC advertisements. The URL, in order to be effective, should take the consumer to the company’s product page, unless the company’s homepage acts second to a product page.</p>

<p><strong>Tip:</strong> Consider camel casing each word and using your target keyword in the display URL to increase click through rate. Example: www.AcmeWidgetCompany.com/Blue-Widgets</p>

<p>In this example, we&#8217;ll use Google AdWords to demonstrate proper PPC A/B testing or split testing. In order for the campaign to work to its maximum potential, the user must show variations by split-testing advertisements. Most users will not have access to complex tools, but low-tech variations can be run from something as simple as an Excel spreadsheet.</p>

<p><strong>Tip:</strong> At the initial stage, dynamic insertion should be ignored and ad optimization should be turned off, since we want all advertisements to be shown with equal probability.</p>

<p>Assuming that only the advertisement and not the landing page is being tested; you can come up with a table that looks something like this:</p>

<table border=1 width=100% bordercolor="#e5e5e5" style="margin-top:20px;margin-bottom:20px;" width="100%" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="3">
  <tbody>
    <tr style="background-color:#f3f3f3;">
      <th>Ad</th>
      <th>Title</th>
      <th>Description 1</th>
      <th>Description 2</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>4</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>5</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>6</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>7</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>8</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>2</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<p>Following exponential numbers, we just created 8 advertisements with 2 variations on each line. As the number of variations increase, the numbers go up, and this is where the testing comes in. As far as the testing goes, there are some important factors we need to keep in mind. These consist of:</p>

<ul>
<li>All variations must be tested simultaneously to reduce time-based factors that may result in biased results.</li>
<li>Test one thing at a time, so you can tell what’s affecting the success of your advertisements.</li>
<li>Let the numbers decide what’s right, not your instincts.</li>
<li>Test your advertisements long enough. For example, depending upon the type of product the company has to offer, the advertisement may get less than 100 impressions a day, or 10,000 impressions a week. In any case, you must have a few thousand impressions to reach an unbiased conclusion. Also, any special events like holidays coming up should be taken into account, since these usually result in a different type of traffic.</li>
</ul>


<p>Keep in mind that advertisements and landing pages will be directly related to each other, and different advertisement and landing page combinations can lead to different conversion rates.</p>

<p>Results can also be customized to show you what you&#8217;re looking for. Custom reports can help you organize your reports by CTR, number and rate of transactions, and total profits. Reports like transaction rates also help you keep track of how many consumers are returning customers.</p>

<p>A/B testing may seem like a lot of work, but it will prove beneficial in the long run, since it helps you get the most out of your advertising budget. Having access to advanced toolsets will definitely help, but low-scale split-testing may prove just as good.</p>

<p>Have you signed up for AdProof, yet? AdProof lets you A/B test your ads in minutes. AdProof makes A/B testing PPC ads a walk in the park and costs less than a cup of coffee. <a href="http://adproof.com">Sign up and get your first ad test for free</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write Better Calls to Action]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/conversion/write-better-calls-to-action/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-10T21:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/conversion/write-better-calls-to-action</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Calls to action play a large role in all types of marketing. Even though they are just a simple, short piece of text, they still are significant for adverts and marketing schemes. They encourage the reader, or more accurately the potential customer, to do something particularly for the company – “buy, start a trial, download, call now, etc.” When calls to action are placed on websites, they make sure that the reader just does not browse the site for no use at all – they actually get the person to do something. Calls to action should be used in all forms of marketing – online websites, marketing emails, brochures, and anywhere else where they can receive attention from the reader. Also, it would always be preferable if the calls to action are highlighted or popping out in some way so that they can’t be missed.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Before Making Your CTA, Remember That…</h2>

<ul>
<li>If you want higher conversions from your CTA, then it would be best to add extra worth and significance in your calls to action. The idea is to make the readers feel as if it is for their benefit, not the company’s.</li>
<li>Even the littlest change in your call to action can make a lot of difference. For example, if the CTA says “Order now” for a product it would not get as many conversions as it would if it said “Get now”. Again, the simple idea is to make the reader feel encouraged and mimic the action that is being conveyed through a text-based sentence.</li>
<li>One thing should always be clear to you before you create your CTA: your desired customer response (DCR). DCR relates to what you want the people to do after they have seen your call to action.</li>
<li>All your calls to action should be perfectly clear. So clear that even an eight year old would not have a problem in understanding them. Also, the CTA should be simple and should only have one basic task it wants the reader to do.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Classic Calls to Action</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Download Now</strong> - This call to action focuses on downloading, which is simple for everyone and “now” which makes people know their time won’t be wasted.</li>
<li><strong>Get a Free…</strong> - As obvious, since people love free stuff, this CTA is perfect for marketing and encouraging people.</li>
<li><strong>Join Now</strong> - This call to action works great for social network sites or membership sites.</li>
<li><strong>Click Here</strong> - Focuses on the fact that it’s just a click away and is right there in front of the customer.</li>
<li><strong>Start Your Trial</strong> - Trial periods in general are appetizing for the customers; they don’t require any permanent commitment and the people are free to make their own decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Money Back Guarantee</strong> - This is a great call to action as the readers can feel assured that if they don’t like the product they placed, they can still get their money back, which enforces more people to buy without thinking so much.</li>
<li><strong>Satisfaction Guaranteed</strong> - Anything which comes with satisfaction, whether it may be guaranteed by the company or other acquaintances that have used it, is always easy to buy and this is exactly what this CTA does.</li>
</ul>


<p>A lot of us believe that it is just a probability, and that these CTAs do not really matter. But it is proven scientifically that human psychology reacts according to what it makes contact with. Therefore majority of the people actually react according to the text they read, they have a propensity of mimicking calls to action if they are convincing enough. It is of course worth the effort, work hard on it because eventually it will prove to increase your business conversion rate immensely.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write Better Headlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/write-better-headlines/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T02:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/write-better-headlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Writing effective headlines are a great way to make your article stand out. Remember that a headline is just one word or phrase that summarizes an article or the key point of your content. It is meant to clarify to the audience, what you are going to talk about. It is an effective communication tool to grab the readers&#8217; attentions. Once the reader has been reeled in, it is your article’s job to keep the readers engaged.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Research Popular Headlines</h2>

<p>Would not it be a waste for a captivating article to be left unread? First things first: you need to understand your target audience. A great headline to you might not be as eye-catching to them.  To help you understand them, study headlines of other articles or the aforementioned template headings that have proven to exert a pull on the readers. Do not copy them, but instead dissect them and learn how they were structured to become skilled at creating your own catchy headings. Next, choose the right words and phrases; keep your readers at bay because a dull and boring caption will not even make them give your article a second glance.</p>

<p>Use an intriguing rhetorical question as your headline.  If your question is worded carefully it’ll be easy to hold the audience. You can simply make a strong statement that clearly demonstrates that what the content will further define in your article.</p>

<h2>5 Headline Tips</h2>

<p>Attention is crafted via a good header. So, what are some good tips to develop an interesting headline for a great article?</p>

<ul>
<li>Starting off with “Who Wouldn&#8217;t Want&#8230;&#8221; is a classic when the article is about a product or about something that needs to happen, because people will always desire something that someone else has and they do not.</li>
<li>Another phrase that can be used is &#8220;The Secret of&#8230;&#8221;. This is a powerful attention-grabber, as readers will instantly want to get in on this &#8216;secret&#8217; that your article is about.</li>
<li>People will always appreciate something content that would literally help them, therefore a phrase like &#8220;A Method That’s Helping (specific class or group of people) to (specific action or task that they find difficult) will definitely do the magic trick.</li>
<li>Using &#8220;Little Known Ways to (specific action or task)&#8221; is also one of the effectual ways of constructing a title. This is a more intriguing, uncommon version of “The Secret of&#8230;”.</li>
<li>A popular phrase used by articles that promote a certain product or action or even lifestyle is &#8220;Get Rid of (a specific problem that readers face) Once and For All&#8221;. Take a common problem that your readers face, and tell them that your article can help them overcome it.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Example Headlines</h2>

<ul>
<li>&#8220;Quick and Easy Ways to solve (a specific problem)&#8221; also works since people, you and even I love easy solutions to problems.</li>
<li>&#8220;Now You Can Also Have&#8221; is a very attractive header, because majority of us will always desire more things.</li>
<li>&#8220;Be Like a Celebrity&#8221; is great for articles about beauty/health/fitness.</li>
<li>&#8220;Have or Build Something You Can Be Proud Of!&#8221; appeals to vanity and dissatisfaction.</li>
<li>&#8220;What Everybody Needs To Know about (a specific topic)&#8221; not only attracts people into reading the body of your article, but also challenges them to read the article and test their knowledge on the topic.</li>
</ul>


<h2>KISS Headlines</h2>

<p>Keep it simple stupid (KISS). There are plenty of ways to write an effective headline. But there are certain types of them that have proven to literally attract millions of viewers. The essence of aforementioned information is based on the following simple steps:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn from previous headlines.</li>
<li>Understand your audience.</li>
<li>Test by using headline formulas.</li>
<li>Push it live.</li>
<li>That&#8217;s it!</li>
</ul>


<p>Now you are capable of working out your own headlines.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get 237 Beta Testers For Your Awesome Startup Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/startups/get-237-beta-testers-for-your-awesome-startup-now/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T02:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/startups/get-237-beta-testers-for-your-awesome-startup-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week I entered search mode to find resources to spotlight <a href="http://adproof.com" title="AdProof: A/B Testing for Google Adwords, Bing Ads and Facebook Ads">AdProof</a> and get beta testers. The results were <a href="http://www.udemy.com/blog/beta-testers/">good</a>, <a href="http://www.betabait.com">bad</a> and <a href="http://www.betausersnow.com">ugly</a>.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Top Three Places to Submit Startup</h2>

<p>The 3 places, in order of importance, you need to submit your startup to now:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://betali.st" title="Beta List">Beta List</a></li>
<li><a href="http://startupli.st" title="Startup List">Startup List</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.startupplays.com/" title="Startup Plays">Startup Plays</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Winner #1: Beta List</h2>

<p><a href="http://betali.st/startups/adproof" title="Beta List">Beta List</a> was the first site that showed up for the search:</p>

<p><a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=beta+users+startup&amp;oq=beta+users+startup&amp;aqs=chrome.0.57j62l2.8237&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">beta users startup</a></p>

<p>I signed up using my <a href="https://twitter.com/adproof" title="AdProof on Twitter">AdProof Twitter account</a> and was off to the races. I started reading through the instructions and noticed this text:</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Please note at this time we only accept startups that are not yet publicly accessible. Feel free to submit anyway so we have your info on file for the future. Full details here.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>Crap!!! I need beta users, like yesterday, and this is not helping. I dragged along and then stumbled on a free pass for $15. The pass guarantees publication within 48 hours (only took me a few hours). Here&#8217;s the short story. It cost me $15, yielded 200 beta users, and took less than 24 hours. W00T!</p>

<p><strong>Results:</strong> Currently about 200 sign ups.</p>

<h2>Protip #1</h2>

<p>In all my startup experience I&#8217;ve found it extremely vital to achieve small wins every day. If you&#8217;re not winning, you&#8217;re losing and that&#8217;s not healthy for the psyche. This was my small win that day.</p>

<h2>Winner #2: Startup Plays</h2>

<p>I stumbled on this precious gem after, <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a>, from the awesome <a href="http://www.startupplays.com/" title="Startup Plays">Startup Plays</a>, signed up for the private beta via <a href="http://betali.st/startups/adproof" title="Beta List">Beta List</a>. <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a> emailed me and asked if I&#8217;d like to be featured on his monthly blog post called, <a href="www.startupplays.com/blog/top-35-startups-in-tech-that-techcrunch-missed-out-on-january-2013/" title="Top 35 Startups In Tech that TechCrunch missed out on January 2013">Top 35 Startups In Tech that TechCrunch missed out on January 2013</a>. There&#8217;s no way I&#8217;d pass up on that, so I emailed <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a> back with a short description of <a href="http://adproof.com" title="AdProof: Create High Performing Ads for Google, Bing and Facebook">AdProof</a> and screenshot.</p>

<p>What did I learn here? Reach out to awesome startup bloggers, like <a href="https://twitter.com/Francov88" title="Francov88">@Francov88</a>, on Twitter or email and make it super personal. If they email you first then be sure to respond back within 10 minutes. The goal here is stay fresh in their mind while keeping it super personal.</p>

<p><strong>Results:</strong> Currently about 30 sign ups.</p>

<h2>Protip #2</h2>

<p>Protip: If you&#8217;re not monitoring your brand terms with <a href="http://www.google.com/alerts" title="Google Alerts">Google Alerts</a> and <a href="https://ifttt.com" title="If This, Then That">IFTTT</a> (If This, Then That) then do that now. I&#8217;m currently monitoring my brand terms with Google Alerts using this query:</p>

<ul>
<li>-site:adproof.com &#8220;adproof&#8221;</li>
<li>-site:adproof.com adproof</li>
</ul>


<p>Ive setup a recipe for each Google Alert, using the RSS feed, inside IFTTT to SMS me. Here&#8217;s my recipe if you need: <a href="https://ifttt.com/myrecipes/personal/2774260/share" title="AdProof IFTTT">AdProof IFTTT Google Alert Recipe</a>. Remember to update the title and change the URL to your own Google Alert RSS URL.</p>

<h2>Winner #3: Startup List</h2>

<p>I gotta say, <a href="http://startupli.st/" title="Startup List">Startup List</a> has got their crap together. Not only can you submit your <a href="http://startupli.st/adproof" title="AdProof on Startup List">awesome startup</a>, you can also manage it inside a pretty dashboard. This is a great idea because startups change, ummm, frequently. So if your startup updates the homepage, or you want to tidy up your description, or add a video or even a new social media username, then you can do that here. My initial submission didn&#8217;t get the response necessary to make the homepage, but a quick email to the helpful <a href="thenickfrost" title="Nick Frost from Startup List">@thenickfrost</a> fixed all that. Friendly group of guys over there.  High recommend.</p>

<p><strong>Results:</strong> Currently about 20 sign ups.</p>

<h2>The Bad and Ugly</h2>

<p>I stumbled on a few other sites to submit your startup, but they&#8217;re all stuck in &#8216;pending&#8217;. I think these sites have potential, but are super duper slow in their moderation process.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="inspiredbeta.com" title="Inspired Beta">Inspired Beta</a> - Stuck in &#8216;Your membership account has not been activated yet&#8217; hell.</li>
<li><a href="momb.socio-kybernetics.net" title="Museum of Modern Betas">MoMB or The Museum of Modern Betas</a> - This site appeared to be active during the time, but now I&#8217;m not thinking so much. I sent an email to the author, via the footer, but didn&#8217;t get a response.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Don&#8217;t Miss Next Post</h2>

<p>Stay tuned. You won&#8217;t want to miss the next blog post. I&#8217;m going to show you what worked and what didn&#8217;t when I applied advertising tactics to get beta users. I&#8217;ll show you what worked and what failed miserably. I&#8217;ll show you how I sent over <a href="http://adproof.com" title="Facebook Ads tactic that yielded 250 users in less than 5 minutes">250 users from Facebook Ads in less than 5 minutes</a> for $10. Yes, I used <a href="http://adproof.com" title="AdProof: A/B Testing for Google Adwords, Bing Ads and Facebook Ads">AdProof</a>. Which reminds me… are you <a href="http://adproof.com" title="Sign up for AdProof private beta">signed up for our private beta</a>, yet? We&#8217;re closing the private beta once we reach 1,000.</p>

<h2>Sharing is Caring Blah, Blah, Blah</h2>

<p>If you enjoyed this post then share it or else… just kidding. No, seriously, please share the post. Thanks ;-)</p>

<h2>Need Help?</h2>

<p>I learned a ton about getting beta users with this exercise. So if you need any tips, please shoot a tweet to <a href="http://twitter.com/jonathannelson" title="Message on @jonathannelson on Twitter">@jonathannelson</a> and I promise to respond.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ad Copy Demystified]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/ad-copy-demystified/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T01:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/advertising/ad-copy-demystified</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What’s an advertisement? An advertisement is any notice or announcement to promote an idea, product, service or an event. It could be announced through the television, radio, or the internet. There are endless possibilities when it comes to how you want to advertise your item or idea. Some people go through vigorous pains and have huge events to officially announce their items while others do it more quietly on television or internet. Not only do advertisements help customers getting familiarized with the product but also help the company that is promoting it. Something more efficient than an advertisement is an advertising copy; or Ad copy for short. But what is an advertising copy?</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>What Exactly Is Ad Copy?</h2>

<p>Advertising copy can be found anywhere on the internet. In the search results. In your Facebook or Twitter feed. They are created specifically to catch someone’s eyes, and eventually make said person click the ad copy. Usually Ad copies are either contextual or pay per click. Ad copies can be actually anything; from catchy product titles to enticing product pictures with text on them. Text of the ad copy is usually the second or third line of an ad displayed on a search engine result page or any other web page. Most ad copy makers usually add keywords about usage of the product along with the few catchy lines. This is to gather more audience for their ads. When a person searches a specific keyword on a search engine they will be linked to the ad copy if it has anything to do with it.</p>

<h2>Ad Copy – A Bridge Between Search Results and Websites</h2>

<p>Present time marketing is becoming more challenging to handle. With each passing day it is becoming more aggressive. Since there is always competition in the marketplace you need to make sure that your ad copies are distinct, unique and eye catching. It basically serves as the communication point between the search results and your website. The more you make your ad copies attractive the more appealing they will be towards everyday consumers. Make sure to include details about your product in your ad copy while you are at it, keep the FAQs of the general audience in mind. For example, how helpful it is compared to other products, advantages, disadvantages but more importantly, keep it short and simple. Because the last thing you would want is a dull ad that no one pays attention to.</p>

<h2>What’s the Goal of Your Ad?</h2>

<p>Focus on the goal you are creating an ad for. Interest a customer by informing them how your product can change their life, as clearly as possible. This is a vital ingredient for the ad copy. You need to include how far superior your item is towards others and how much more it can help your customers in changing their life. But do this indirectly as you do not want to stir trouble by openly bashing against a specific product or company. Your main goal should be to define the unique points of your product/service since they tend to attract customers into making a direct action. The probability rises if there is call to actions in your ads because the viewers are keen to mimic them.</p>

<p>Building credibility should be one of your advertisement goals. Offer the audience believability about the product, brand, or idea that you are advertising about. If your product is linked to everyday life it’ll have a better chance of being bought.</p>

<h2>Details, Details, Details</h2>

<p>Another core ingredient in your ad copy is grammar and punctuation. This is extremely important. You need to use simple words to get your idea crystal-clear to the audience. Do not pick lengthy words at random and put them in your ad copy thinking it’ll make it sound intelligent. It won’t. It also won’t help people understand what you’re talking about. Be specific and straight to the point. Remember you want your product to make an impression on people.</p>

<h2>Test-Drive your Ad</h2>

<p>At last before ever going out to make an ad copy or to even think about advertising your time you need to test your product, item, or idea. Will it attract everyday consumers? Does it spark an interest in someone? What things is it capable that other products are not. Ask yourself these questions before you advertise. More importantly do not promise consumers anything about your item. It is bad for your company image if you’re caught lying. Remember, make a good impression on people and they will definitely come back for more.</p>

<h2>Have You Signed Up for AdProof Yet?</h2>

<p>AdProof is the first test-driven advertising platform that lets ad buyers test before they spend. Ad buyers can now A/B test any ad group for just a $1. AdProof is super fast. No more wasted hours waiting for data or approval of ads. You’ll get results back in minutes. AdProof supports all ad types. Test your PPC ads, display ads, and social media ad campaigns. AdProof supports all devices. Optimize your ads for desktops &amp; laptops, mobile devices and tablets.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
