<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: career | The @AdProof Marketing Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/./career/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-19T10:07:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.adproof.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[AdProof]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Use Sales Techniques to Sell Yourself In Interviews]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/career/how-to-use-sales-techniques-to-sell-yourself-in-interviews/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-17T23:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/career/how-to-use-sales-techniques-to-sell-yourself-in-interviews</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are many steps that can be suggested so as to get in the right mindset, such as reviewing and going through all the feats you have accomplished and done over the past years. When reviewing this, you can include all the awards that you have received, the praises that you have been given, thank you notes, pats on the back from mentors etc., basically you’re including all the things that have made you glorified. Another step would be to assess the qualities that led you to your accomplishments. Make up a story that doesn’t take more than a few minutes to tell and tell it in the interview, at the appropriate time, of course.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Try to remember a time when you didn’t have any experience but still put in your best shop and got results that were better than expected and make a 1-2 minute story up for that, too. Then, try to exercise a bit before the interview to warm you up. Wear clothes that suit you or have been complimented a lot and make sure they fit the “interview” environment. Go through the company’s webpage before the interview so that everything stays fresh in your mind and you can also recognize some questions that might be asked to you in the interview so you’ll be ready for them. Lastly, when you walk into the company, blast everyone with confident smiles; show them that you believe that you’re perfect for them, and get ready to get the job.</p>

<h2>Conduct Specific Research Prior To The Interview</h2>

<h3>Start with the job description</h3>

<p>Every company will be expecting from the candidates that they’ll have gone through the whole details about the job before not just the interview, but before applying altogether. So it’s a good idea to understand and know your potential job details.</p>

<h3>Use the Internet</h3>

<p>Open up the company’s webpage and go through it. Also check out all the related news about the company on other sites. See what the company is renowned for, what the company’s image is and what is it about to do in the future etc.</p>

<p>Check out your interviewers’ pages on the website and on other social sites as well. See what they do within the company; what tasks they manage, what business areas do they manage, what is prominent in their role in the company, etc.</p>

<h3>Read the small print</h3>

<p>It may not sound relevant, but it is; when on the company’s site, see the sitemap and Investor Relations. There is a lot of information there, surprisingly. See the business’s performance and what their turnover/share price is. Getting extra information sure won’t hurt!</p>

<h3>Connect through LinkedIn</h3>

<p>LinkedIn is a good place to meet people of the business and they might be happy to have a talk with you which can help. Go to your connections and shared connections and gain access to more people.</p>

<h3>Watch the news</h3>

<p>Keep an eye on the news to see if there’s any mention of the company or your interviewers. If you notice anything, see why they’re mentioned, where and with whom they are. See what the company’s most recent progress is and what fields they’re aiming for. If you see your interviewers, see what the news say about them and their role in the business.</p>

<h3>Get on the phone</h3>

<p>Ring up the company’s HR field or reception and inquire about the business, its role, the department, and how the company is keeping up in the commerce area. They can help you a lot and have surprisingly a lot of information.</p>

<h3>What does your agency know?</h3>

<p>If some agency has gotten you this job vacancy, then ask them some questions such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>What types of interviewers are there, what’s their attitude and method of asking?</li>
<li>What is happening with the company these days?</li>
<li>What kind of a person do they want?</li>
<li>Why has this agency chosen me for this job?</li>
<li>Are there other people who’ve been given this chance? If yes, how many?</li>
<li>If so, then how did they do? What were they asked and what went fine/wrong with them?</li>
<li>Does this business want more people for other fields?</li>
</ul>


<h2>The Leadership Skills Required For Advancing A Two-Way Interview</h2>

<p>To be a good leader, your basic leadership skill should be the ability to get people to listen and keep up focus upon an aim, along with being able to innovate and build up new ideas or ways for the business or the people to follow. Being persuasive and influential, showing integrity, building a new vision, innovating, moving the business forward and being firm on your aim are all within good leadership skills.</p>

<p>When on an interview, the candidates will be expected to show how they have these abilities and skills in them. The interviewers will want examples to be sure that you are competent enough. Your aim in the interview will be not just to give your word, but also to prove that you have these leadership skills in you. If you already have these skills in you, then proving them to the interviewers won’t be much of a problem.</p>

<h2>Specific Questions You Must Ask On The Interview</h2>

<p>The company asks you questions in an interview to see whether you fit their requirements or not, but that doesn’t mean that you can’t make sure whether the company fits your requirement or not. As an able person, you have all the rights to place a few queries of your own.</p>

<p>Some proper questions can be:</p>

<ul>
<li>What’s a typical day/week for this job like?</li>
<li>Is this position a new one? If not, where did the former employee advance to?</li>
<li>In what way does this company do its management?</li>
<li>How many other people also work in this department?</li>
<li>Is there any chance of relocation?</li>
<li>Am I expected to work overtime sometimes?</li>
<li>What is the great thing about working here?</li>
<li>How can a person advance to an even better position?</li>
<li>If I do get this position, from when shall I start?</li>
<li>When should I expect to hear from you?</li>
<li>Do you need to know anything else about me?</li>
</ul>


<h2>Strategies for Negotiation</h2>

<p>When being offered a salary, most of the employers never make their best offer initially and the candidates who negotiate are the ones that end up with a higher salary. If you negotiate with the employers sensibly, it will also make you look like an experience candidate. Way before going to the interview, you can do some work for your negotiation – try going through these steps to do so...</p>

<p><strong>During The Interview</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Research and find out about the company’s salary ranges beforehand then think out your negotiation reasonably.</li>
<li>Don’t start talking about the salary too early; once you get the idea that you’re going to be given this job, or they tell you it, then you talk about salaries.</li>
<li>Try avoiding the question about your salary requirements. If you can’t avoid it, then give a diplomatic answer and don’t give a fixed number.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>When Talking About the Offer</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Put your wanted salary before they offer you one. This step will begin the negotiation process.</li>
<li>If they aren’t agreeing to your salary, then start negotiating for extra things like free education or medical.</li>
<li>Show them that you’re valuable to them and how you can increase their business and profit.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Steer Conversation To Learn What The Company Is Seeking</h2>

<p>The most basic traits employers need in their hires are enthusiasm, professionalism, and confidence. These are the traits that can be judged within a minute of the candidate entering the room. Confidence is especially appreciated; a candidate should always look as if he/she is in control and should be confident of all the homework they’ve done. Also, people who look as if they are capable and talk intellectually, too are also appreciated. Tactically including all your work experience and skills in interview conversations is the trait of a self-monitoring person and companies like having self-monitoring people working for them. Don’t hold yourself back thinking that telling about your successes will be showing off; if you do it in the right way, it’ll be fine. Displaying yourself as an eager and curious person will not, as per popular belief, make you unattractive to the employers. In fact, it will help you a lot since employers like passionate and curious people since they agree to new challenges without a frown and truly try to work hard and learn.</p>

<h2>Selling Strategies Designed To Get You Hired</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Thinking Critically:</strong> Being logical and reasonable and evaluating the plus and minus points of various solutions or results of problems.</li>
<li><strong>Problem Solving Abilities:</strong> Recognizing big issues and assessing everything thoroughly to come up with suitable solutions.</li>
<li><strong>Making Solid Judgments:</strong> Going through relative costs and advantages of taking some action and then making the decision.</li>
<li><strong>Listening Attentively:</strong> Paying attention to what people are saying and taking time out to understand the points they are making, asking questions at the right time and not interjecting.</li>
<li><strong>Computers and Electronics:</strong> Knowing about computers and their components as well as other electronics is a great selling strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Math:</strong> Knowing your algebra, geometry, statistics, arithmetic, calculus and their application.</li>
<li><strong>Evaluation of Operations and Systems:</strong> Identifying how a system should process and how changes can influence the results.</li>
<li><strong>Observing:</strong> Keeping check of your performance, other workers’ or the company’s itself to make corrections and improvements.</li>
<li><strong>Programming:</strong> Knowing how to write computer programs for a lot of purposes.</li>
<li><strong>Marketing:</strong> Having knowledge about the ways of displaying, advertising and selling products or services. Having a sense of marketing techniques, sales tactics, and sales control is also included in this strategy.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
