<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: copywriting | The @AdProof Marketing Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/./copywriting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-18T01:37:01-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.adproof.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[AdProof]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 Tips to Writing Copy That Sells]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/7-tips-to-writing-copy-that-sells/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-17T22:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/7-tips-to-writing-copy-that-sells</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For marketing, offers are a big deal; they promote, they lure consumers and they give leads. But, not all offers do so; many of them tend to fail. Those that fail are the ones that aren’t directed right. To create good copy, you need to keep in mind that there are some vital steps that should be ensured before getting started.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>1. Aim Outside The Box</h2>

<p>The product that is being represented deserves to be given proper promotion, because if you don’t fight for it to be sold, then the people won’t fight to buy it either. One thing should always be clear to you that even the littlest thing can affect your copy and totally kill it so you can’t afford it to be less than perfect. It sounds intimidating but it is significant. If you don’t think you have the capability of writing a perfect copy, then get someone else to do it; it would be better than taking a risk.</p>

<h2>2. Research!</h2>

<p>If you want perfect copy, you need to know how your target audience thinks; what they want, how they want, etc. needs to be understood so that you can meet their needs. Knowing your audience requires time – time spent on research. Without it, you’re just be taking chances and these chances can cost you.</p>

<h2>3. Be Nice To Your Consumers</h2>

<p>Everybody likes being treated nicely. You not doing so would lead to pissed off or disappointed customers and anybody who’s mad or let down is bound to turn away from your product, or maybe even your whole business altogether. If they’re given respect, they’ll give respect to you in return, it’s as simple as that. The same attitude to be set in your copy – that the consumers are your equals or maybe even above you since you’re the one who wants them to buy.</p>

<h2>4. Strong Headline Is Vital</h2>

<p>Headlines can work miracles; they’re one part of your copy that must be perfect. It should be attention seeking, interesting and promising. A few tips for strong headlines are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use the headline templates that have gained a lot of response before.</li>
<li>Promise an attractive benefit to the readers, to keep their interest.</li>
<li>Try out different headlines among some and see which one is the best.</li>
</ul>


<h2>5. Pay Attention To Your Sale</h2>

<p>Only after you are totally attentive to your sale should you focus on other factors. More than half of the people only give adverts a glance or so – it’s natural, humans are always in a hurry. So the idea is to make sure that your sale message gets across to the reader in just a glance too. Your main aim should be on making them see the product and the benefits it could bring them; these points shouldn’t be hidden within other unnecessary lines, they should be the main points.</p>

<h2>6. Make Your Copy Informative, Not Rubbish</h2>

<p>Your copy should always explain the product and at the same time explain why the people should buy it. Nobody buys anything without a reason, so your copy should be the one to make them see the reason. The question “why?” is always there – and you have to answer it, in the best way possible:</p>

<ul>
<li>Why is the product necessary?</li>
<li>Why is it a good buy?</li>
<li>Why is the product for them?</li>
<li>Why should they buy this specifically from you?</li>
</ul>


<p>These are some examples of the ever present why’s in a consumer’s mind. To answer them all, you need to do one thing: make the copy informative.</p>

<h2>7. Sales Copy Is Vital – Never Forget That</h2>

<p>Overlooking your copy’s significance is probably one of the biggest mistakes ever in marketing. One must never let its importance slip by. Many business owners write down a few lines, check the grammar and send it to be seen by the eye of the consumers. Then they bite their lip and wonder why they didn’t get any significant response. You need to look after and care for your copy, only then can you produce a successful copy. Caring for them is time and energy consuming – businessmen can spend weeks just to create the headline and take months to write the body of it but it’s nothing shocking – at least not to the person who recognizes the importance of offers and how they need to be given attention.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Write Better Headlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/write-better-headlines/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T02:31:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.adproof.com/copywriting/write-better-headlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Writing effective headlines are a great way to make your article stand out. Remember that a headline is just one word or phrase that summarizes an article or the key point of your content. It is meant to clarify to the audience, what you are going to talk about. It is an effective communication tool to grab the readers' attentions. Once the reader has been reeled in, it is your article’s job to keep the readers engaged.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Research Popular Headlines</h2>

<p>Would not it be a waste for a captivating article to be left unread? First things first: you need to understand your target audience. A great headline to you might not be as eye-catching to them.  To help you understand them, study headlines of other articles or the aforementioned template headings that have proven to exert a pull on the readers. Do not copy them, but instead dissect them and learn how they were structured to become skilled at creating your own catchy headings. Next, choose the right words and phrases; keep your readers at bay because a dull and boring caption will not even make them give your article a second glance.</p>

<p>Use an intriguing rhetorical question as your headline.  If your question is worded carefully it’ll be easy to hold the audience. You can simply make a strong statement that clearly demonstrates that what the content will further define in your article.</p>

<h2>5 Headline Tips</h2>

<p>Attention is crafted via a good header. So, what are some good tips to develop an interesting headline for a great article?</p>

<ul>
<li>Starting off with “Who Wouldn't Want..." is a classic when the article is about a product or about something that needs to happen, because people will always desire something that someone else has and they do not.</li>
<li>Another phrase that can be used is "The Secret of...". This is a powerful attention-grabber, as readers will instantly want to get in on this 'secret' that your article is about.</li>
<li>People will always appreciate something content that would literally help them, therefore a phrase like "A Method That’s Helping (specific class or group of people) to (specific action or task that they find difficult) will definitely do the magic trick.</li>
<li>Using "Little Known Ways to (specific action or task)" is also one of the effectual ways of constructing a title. This is a more intriguing, uncommon version of “The Secret of...”.</li>
<li>A popular phrase used by articles that promote a certain product or action or even lifestyle is "Get Rid of (a specific problem that readers face) Once and For All". Take a common problem that your readers face, and tell them that your article can help them overcome it.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Example Headlines</h2>

<ul>
<li>"Quick and Easy Ways to solve (a specific problem)" also works since people, you and even I love easy solutions to problems.</li>
<li>"Now You Can Also Have" is a very attractive header, because majority of us will always desire more things.</li>
<li>"Be Like a Celebrity" is great for articles about beauty/health/fitness.</li>
<li>"Have or Build Something You Can Be Proud Of!" appeals to vanity and dissatisfaction.</li>
<li>"What Everybody Needs To Know about (a specific topic)" not only attracts people into reading the body of your article, but also challenges them to read the article and test their knowledge on the topic.</li>
</ul>


<h2>KISS Headlines</h2>

<p>Keep it simple stupid (KISS). There are plenty of ways to write an effective headline. But there are certain types of them that have proven to literally attract millions of viewers. The essence of aforementioned information is based on the following simple steps:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn from previous headlines.</li>
<li>Understand your audience.</li>
<li>Test by using headline formulas.</li>
<li>Push it live.</li>
<li>That's it!</li>
</ul>


<p>Now you are capable of working out your own headlines.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
